Rahul Sekhar

93. 30th cross road Banashankari Stage 2 Bangalore - 560070, India ⋈ sekhar.rahul@gmail.com

I take pride in my work and involve myself wholeheartedly in everything I do. Seeing a problem tackled completely, simply and elegantly gives me great satisfaction.

Skills

Programming Languages

In-depth knowledge of Javascript, Ruby, HTML and CSS. Experience with SQL, Python, PHP and shell

Frameworks

In-depth experience with AngularJS, Rails and Wordpress. Experience with Node.js, BackboneJS and Umbraco. Currently learning React and experimenting with it in personal projects.

Process

A strong focus on organisation and maintainability. Programming is essentially management of complexity and I have worked on the skills needed to achieve this.

Modular, readable, documented code are priorities as well as an efficient development process with strong code conventions and continuous integration.

Methodology

Having worked with Agile Scrum and seen its benefits, I aim to further develop my knowledge and experience of Agile methodology.

Web I make it a point to keep track of new developments and techniques in the constantly changing web world. I have experience with designing REST APIs, front end optimisation and responsiveness.

I believe automated testing is a necessity. Experience with BDD, TDD and unit and integration testing using Jasmine, RSpec, Cucumber and Selenium.

Experience with ES6, build processes with webpack, grunt and gulp, SASS and LESS, and GIT. Continuous integration with Jenkins and travis-ci. Setup and management of linux based servers.

Personal I am straightforward and easy to get along with, and am able to convey ideas clearly without jargon. I have led and mentored a small team of developers.

Fluent in English as my primary language. Conversational knowledge of Hindi and Spanish.

Work Experience

2016-current Full Stack Developer, Freelance.

I am currently working with an independent team on a six-month long website redesign project for ILFS, India. As the technical team within ILFS has worked exclusively with Microsoft technology, we're building the website using Umbraco (a CMS based on the ASP.NET framework, with an AngularJS based backend UI) to ease future maintenance.

2015-2016

Lead Front End Developer, Nutanix, Bangalore.

I led a team of front end developers at Nutanix within an excellent team of engineers. We worked on the interface for a number of technical tools including sizing and quote generation for clusters, automated deployment and migration of workloads and cluster healthchecks. My effort in improving the front end development process was greatly appreciated by the team. My work here involved:

- Front end architectural decisions based on the requirements of each tool.
- Agile, scrum based methodology with two-week sprints for each project.
- Monitoring code quality across multiple simultaneous projects.
- Robust and well designed interfaces as the company prioritised design and UX.
- Interfacing with designers, stakeholders and technical experts on tool designs.

- Working closely with the design team at the company headquarters in San Jose, USA. Travelled to San Jose to explore and kick-off a collaborative project with the team there.
- Refactoring and improving the workflow for legacy projects.
- Introduced TDD as a development approach and converted an untested codebase to one with complete test coverage.

2012–2015 Full Stack Developer, Kairi Studios, Bangalore.

At Kairi Studios I worked on webapps and websites for our clients from end to end – technical design, development and deployment. While I worked with the full stack here, due to the nature of our projects my focus was on front-end development. We received appreciation for our user-friendly interfaces, and the maintainability and robustness of our output.

Our projects included a redesign and extensive administration interface for NCF India, an internal academics and journaling system for small schools, and an online store for childrens books. My work at Kairi involved:

- Architectural decisions based on client requirements.
- Behaviour driven development, with user focused stories and automated testing.
- Projects using AngularJS, Ruby on Rails and Wordpress.
- Responsive, mobile-friendly layouts.
- · Documentation and maintenance of projects.

2011–2012 **Full Stack Developer**, Freelance.

I put together websites in collaboration with some very talented designers in my initial time as a freelance developer. I made it a point to explore new technologies, frameworks, tools and techniques in an effort to stay up-to-date and remain flexible in my infrastructure choices, which has served me well.

Education

2007–2011 BMS College of Engineering, Bangalore.

B.E. in Telecommunication Engineering – First Class

1995–2007 The Valley School, Bangalore.

Indian School Certificate (ISC) - First class

Other Interests

Fitness A hobby cyclist and runner, I've taken part in cycle tours and numerous runs. Physical fitness is a priority as I believe creativity and mental fitness stem from this base.

Music A passionate guitarist, I play in an acoustic duo called Nothing Rhymed. I have also been avidly involved in Tango dancing.

Hiking I enjoy treks and have completed a basic mountaineering course at the Himalayan Mountaineering Institute, Darjeeling.

Electronics I enjoy hobby electronics, and have worked on small projects using Arduinos.